Register of the O. Edmund Clubb Papers, 1940-1988
Hoover Institution Archives
O. Edmund Clubb Papers,
1940-1988
93003
Clubb, O. Edmund (Oliver Edmund), 1901-
25 manuscript boxes, 9 card file boxes (12.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, loyalty- security board hearing transcripts, conference papers and agenda, and printed matter, relating to Sino-American relations; the post- World War II loyalty-security program in the Department of State; various aspects of Chinese history and politics, especially in the twentieth century; and American policy during the Vietnamese War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
China--Foreign relations--United States; United States--Foreign relations--China; China--History; China--Politics and government--20th century; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975; China; United States--Foreign relations; United States--Politics and government; United States. Dept. of State; Internal security--United States; Diplomats--United States
Biography
American diplomat and political scientist; consul general, Peking, China, 1947-1950; director, Office of Chinese Affairs, Department of State, 1950-1952
Biographical Note
1901 February 16 Born, South Park, Minnesota
1927 Receives bachelor's degree, University of Minnesota
1928-1952 Foreign service officer, U.S. Department of State, including term as Consul General, Beijing
1951 Faces charges of "disloyalty" during McCarthy period and is suspended from the China desk of the State Department
1952 Suspension is overturned on appeal by Clubb, who nonetheless resigns from the State Department
1959-1966 Visiting lecturer at Columbia University, Brooklyn College, New York University, the New School for Social Research, and Cornell University
1964 Author, 20th Century China
1971 Author, China and Russia: The 'Great Game'
Scope and Content
Received at the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993, the O. Edmund Clubb Papers consist primarily of writings, correspondence, and research materials relating to Clubb's lifelong interest in the politics and history of China. From the time of his experience as Foreign Service officer in China, Clubb wrote extensively on issues of China policy, and in particular Sino-American relations. Having been a "China Hand," Clubb had been a direct witness to the Chinese civil war and was critical of unconditional American support for the forces of Chiang Kai-shek in this conflict. Clubb's position would later bring him difficulties in terms of his career in the State Department.
During the McCarthy period, Clubb faced accusations of "disloyalty" and was suspended from his policy position within the State Department (a transcript of Clubb's hearing before the Loyalty Security Board can be found in the Biographical File). Although he was later vindicated on the appeal of his suspension, he resigned from the Foreign Service and pursued a career as a writer and academic, concentrating again on issues relating to China. His writings reflect a consistent viewpoint challenging American foreign policy during the Cold War, and he emerged as an early critic of the American intervention in Vietnam.
In presenting Clubb's scholarly and journalistic publications in one place, the collection affords researchers the opportunity to trace the development of Clubb's thinking on issues of foreign policy and Chinese politics. The correspondence also reveals Clubb's relations with other China scholars and his role as a foreign policy adviser to several prominent American politicians.
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1951-1981. (Box 1)
  Articles, bibliographies, biographies, certificate, correspondence, directories, leaflet, map, permit, photo, program, records, transcripts, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1953-1988. (Boxes 1-8)
  Letters arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1940-1983. (Boxes 9-22)
  Articles, books, correspondence, notes, outlines, and research material, arranged chronologically by title
- ACADEMIC FILE, 1959-1965. (Box 22)
  Correspondence, memoranda, and outlines, arranged alphabetically by name of institution
- MARIANN CLUBB FILE, 1946-1982. (Boxes 22-23)
  Autobiography and correspondence, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- SUBJECT FILE, 1956-1983. (Boxes 23-25)
  Correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
- PHOTOGRAPH, n.d. (Box 25)
  One print depicting O. Edmund Clubb
- CARD INDEX FILE, n.d. (Boxes 26-35)
  Lecture outlines and research notes, unsorted
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1951-1981
  - Articles and clippings, 1952-1981 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, 1977-1981 (Folder 2.)
  - Biographies
    - General, 1958-1976 (Folder 3)
    - Transcript of an interview conducted by Sheila Lalwani for a proposed biography of Clubb, 1978. Includes correspondence (Folder 4)
  - Directories, relating mainly to Clubb's foreign service career, 1951-1975 (Folder 5)
  - Legal transcripts relating to hearings concerning Clubb conducted by the Loyalty Security Board of the Department of State, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Personal records, relating to financial, legal, and real estate matters, 1959-1974. Certificate, correspondence, survey map, and transcripts (Folder 7)
  - Miscellany, 1961-1970(?) International driving permit, leaflet, and program (Folder 8)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1953-1988.
  Includes enclosures and personal memoranda
  - General
    - General, 1956-1983
      - A (Box 1., Folder 9)
      - B (Folder 10)
      - C (Folder 11)
      - D (Folder 12)
      - E (Folder 13)
      - F (Folder 14)
      - G (Folder 15)
      - H (Folder 16)
      - I (Folder 17)
      - J (Folder 18)
      - K (Folder 19)
      - L (Folder 20)
      - M (Folder 21)
      - N (Folder 22)
      - P (Folder 23)
      - R (Folder 24)
      - S (Folder 25)
      - T (Folder 26)
      - U (Folder 27)
      - V (Folder 28)
      - W (Folder 29)
      - Y (Folder 30)
    - Correspondence relating to public speaking engagements
      - 1955-1961 (Box 2., Folder 1)
      - 1962 (Folder 2)
      - 1963 (Folder 3)
      - 1964 (Folder 4)
      - 1965
      - January-June (Folder 5)
      - July-December (Folder 6)
      - 1966 (Box 3., Folder 1)
      - 1967
      - January-June (Folder 2)
      - July-December (Folder 3)
      - 1968 (Folder 4)
      - 1969 (Folder 5)
      - 1970 (Folder 6)
      - 1971 (Folder 7)
      - 1972 (Box 4., Folder 1)
      - 1973-1975 (Folder 2)
      - 1978-1979 (Folder 3)
    - Unidentified (Folder 4)
    - Adams, Taylor, 1962-1976 (Folder 5)
    - Alexander-Sinclair, John, 1963-1977 (Folder 6)
    - Anderson, Jack, 1971-1972 (Folder 7)
    - Armstrong, Eunice B., 1956 (Folder 8)
    - Atkinson, Brooks, 1973-1977 (Folder 9)
    - The Atlantic, 1959-1971. Includes correspondence with Edward Weeks (Folder 10)
    - The Author's Guild, Inc., 1975 (Folder 11)
    - Bainsfather(?), R., 1967-1978 (Folder 12)
    - Barnett, A. Doak, 1962-1974 (Folder 13)
    - Barrett, David, 1963-1972 (Folder 14)
    - Bateman, Margaret, 1975 (Folder 15)
    - Bingham, Jonathan, 1969-1971 (Folder 16)
    - Blatnik, John, 1957 (Folder 17)
    - Boatwright, Billy, 1958-1977 (Folder 18)
    - Bodde, Derk, 1965-1975 (Folder 19)
    - Bontecu, Eleanor, 1953 (Folder 20)
    - Borg, Dorothy, 1974-1975 (Folder 21)
    - Boyce, Richard Fyfe, 1972-1974 (Folder 22)
    - Burr, Vera, 1967-1976 (Folder 23)
    - Canaday, Frank, 1974-1975 (Folder 24)
    - Capra, Catherine, 1966-1969 (Folder 25)
    - Carlson, Rubie, 1968 (Folder 26)
    - Chang, Rosalind, 1975-1977 (Folder 27)
    - The China Quarterly, 1960-1975. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding articles submitted to this publication (Folder 28)
    - Clubb, Bruce, 1974-1976 (Box 5., Folder 1)
    - Clubb, Oliver Edmund, Jr., 1971-1976 (Folder 2)
    - Clubb family, 1969-1978. Includes correspondence with Clubb's daughter, Zoe, son-in-law, Bill, and granddaughter (Folder 3)
    - Cohen, Elliot, 1975-1978 (Folder 4)
    - Columbia University Press, 1962-1979. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding material published, or projected to be published, by this press (Folder 5)
    - Cornell University Press, 1967 (Folder 6)
    - Crane, Sylvia, 1972-1984 (Folder 7)
    - Crowe, Colin, 1975-1976 (Folder 8)
    - Cumings, Bruce, 1972 (Folder 9)
    - Custer, Benjamin Scott, 1975-1976 (Folder 10)
    - Daniel, Barry, 1976 (Folder 11)
    - Dufour, Pierre, 1958-1978 (Folder 12)
    - Eckhardt, Bob, 1969 (Folder 13)
    - The Economist, 1953. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding material submitted to this publication (Folder 14)
    - Eloesser, L., 1973 (Folder 15)
    - Emmerson, John, 1973 (Folder 16)
    - Epstein, William, 1969-1972 (Folder 17)
    - Fairbank, John K., 1966-1967 (Folder 18)
    - Findley, Paul, 1969 (Folder 19)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1959-1972 (Folder 20)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1964-1977 (Folder 21)
    - Fox, John, 1974-1975 (Folder 22)
    - Fraser, Donald M., 1967-1977 (Folder 23)
    - Frederick A. Praeger, Inc., 1955-1964 (Folder 24)
    - Frillman, Paul and Louise, 1972-1976 (Folder 25)
    - Fulbright, J. W., 1958-1969 (Folder 26)
    - Galenovich, Yuri, 1974-1975 (Folder 27)
    - Gluck, Sidney, 1975 (Folder 28)
    - Gram, Frederick S., 1956-1977 (Folder 29)
    - Griffith, Samuel B., III, 1967-1976 (Folder 30)
    - Gurney, Natalie, 1953 (Folder 31)
    - Hadden, Dick and Frances, 1969-1978 (Folder 32)
    - Halberstam, David, 1972 (Folder 33)
    - Harper's, 1959-1975 (Folder 34)
    - Hellie, Ole, 1967-1976 (Folder 35)
    - Hester, Hugh, 1956-1973 (Folder 36)
    - Historical Abstracts, 1959 (Folder 37)
    - Hitch, S. Herbert, 1973 (Folder 38)
    - Hoose, Harned Pettus, 1976 (Folder 39)
    - Howe, Quincy, 1972 (Folder 40)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1956-1976 (Folder 41)
    - Institute on Man and Science, 1971-1975. Includes correspondence with Everett Clinchy (Folder 42)
    - J. B. Lipincott, Co., 1970 (Box 6., Folder 1)
    - Jacobson, George and Dorothy, 1956-1978 (Folder 2)
    - Jaffa, Herbert, 1967-1971 (Folder 3)
    - Javits, Jacob K., 1958 (Folder 4)
    - Komor, Mathias, 1969-1971 (Folder 5)
    - Kreisky, Fritz and Selma, 1967-1975 (Folder 6)
    - Kuh, Frederick, 1953-1966 (Folder 7)
    - Kuzmin, Viatcheslav, 1967-1969 (Folder 8)
    - Lamb, Lionel, Sir, 1967-1974 (Folder 9)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1972-1976 (Folder 10)
    - Larkcom, Eric and Dorothy Jacobs-Larkcom, 1973-1977 (Folder 11)
    - Lattimore, Owen, 1955 (Folder 12)
    - Leonard, Jane, 1971-1972 (Folder 13)
    - Levi, Warner, 1956 (Folder 14)
    - Lewis, Anthony, 1977 (Folder 15)
    - Lewis, Winston, 1974 (Folder 16)
    - Lowenthal, John, 1977 (Folder 17)
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 1968 (Folder 18)
    - McGovern, George, 1969-1977. See also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 19)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1964-1965 (Folder 20)
    - Mandel, David, 1966-1978 (Folder 21)
    - Medical Aid for Indochina, Inc., 1973 (Folder 22)
    - Melby, John, 1968-1973 (Folder 23)
    - Melman, Seymour, 1975 (Folder 24)
    - Morse, Wayne, 1954-1972 (Folder 25)
    - Nash, Ernest, 1969-1970 (Folder 26)
    - The Nation, 1953-1975. Includes correspondence with Carey McWilliams. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding articles submitted to this publication (Folder 27)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE), 1966-1974 (Folder 28)
    - National Committee on United States-China Relations, Inc., 1966-1975 (Folder 29)
    - The New York Times, 1954-1977. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for letters (published and unpublished) to the editor of this publication (Box 7., Folder 1)
    - The New Yorker, 1973-1974. Includes correspondence with E. J. Kahn (Folder 2)
    - Newman, Robert P., 1977-1978 (Folder 3)
    - Newsweek, 1971 (Folder 4)
    - Oxford University Press, 1978 (Folder 5)
    - Pacific Affairs, 1953 (Folder 6)
    - Porter, Charles, 1970-1976 (Folder 7)
    - The Progressive, 1955-1978. Includes correspondence with Erwin Knoll and Morris Rubin. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding articles submitted to this publication (Folder 8)
    - Random House, Inc., 1972-1974 (Folder 9)
    - The Reporter, 1957-1959 (Folder 10)
    - Rinden, Robert, 1968-1977 (Folder 11)
    - Ritchie, Will and Ella, 1967-1969 (Folder 12)
    - Rouillard, George and Gail, 1972-1973 (Folder 13)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1955 (Folder 14)
    - Ryan, William F., 1970 (Folder 15)
    - Sacharoff, Mark, 1971-1979 (Folder 16)
    - Salisbury, Harrison, 1871-1975 (Folder 17)
    - Salisbury, Larry, 1969 (Folder 18)
    - Scalapino, Robert, 1974-1977. See also SUBJECT FILE for correspondence with Scalapino regarding the platform positions of the Democratic National Committee (Folder 19)
    - Schaller, Michael, 1977 (Folder 20)
    - Schell, Moxie, 1974-1976 (Folder 21)
    - Schell, Orville, Mr. and Mrs., 1967-1975 (Folder 22)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1953 (Folder 23)
    - Selleck, Jameson D., 1977 (Folder 24)
    - Service, John S., 1966-1977 (Folder 25)
    - Smedley, Frederick, 1971-1978 (Folder 26)
    - Snow, Edgar and Lois, 1966-1979 (Folder 27)
    - Time-Life Books, Inc., 1975-1978. Includes correspondence with Charles Osborne and William Goolrick (Box 8., Folder 1)
    - Topping, Seymour, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
    - Tuchman, Barbara, 1971-1974 (Folder 3)
    - University of California Press, 1971-1977 (Folder 4)
    - Vincent, John Carter, Mr. and Mrs., 1966-1975 (Folder 5)
    - Vixseboxse, Jan and Agnes, 1969-1976 (Folder 6)
    - Vogel, William, 1967 (Folder 7)
    - Walker, Mildred, 1972-1975 (Folder 8)
    - War/Peace Report, 1966-1967. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding articles submitted to this publication (Folder 9)
    - Warburg, James P., 1956-1968 (Folder 10)
    - Watkins, James T., IV, 1971 (Folder 11)
    - Watson, Gale and Elva, 1967-1975 (Folder 12)
    - Whiting, Allen, 1956-1972 (Folder 13)
    - Whittaker, Urban, 1961-1962 (Folder 14)
    - Wilbur, C. Martin, 1965 (Folder 15)
    - Williams, Oliver, 1968-1976 (Folder 16)
    - Wohl, Paul, 1970-1972 (Folder 17)
    - Women Strike for Peace, 1966 (Folder 18)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1962-1965 (Folder 19)
    - Worldview, 1972-1983. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for correspondence regarding articles submitted to this publication (Folder 20)
    - Wu, Chaucer, 1957 (Folder 21)
    - Yee, Hubert, 1975 (Folder 22)
    - Yoken, Mel, 1974-1976 (Folder 23)
    - Zeligs, Meyer, 1963-1967. Includes biographical material concerning Clubb (Folder 24)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1940-1983.
  Articles, books, correspondence, notes, outlines, and research material. Dates and titles established on the basis of bibliographies prepared by the author (for bibliographies, see BIOGRAPHICAL FILE)
  - "Across the Formosa Strait," outline for book project, n.d. Typescript (Box 9., Folder 1)
  - "The Aims of U.S. Diplomacy in East Asia," n.d. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "America, Russia, and the Chinese Revolution," n.d. Typescript
  - Chapters 1-2 (Folder 3)
  - Chapters 4-6 (3 is missing) (Folder 4)
  - "The American Foreign Service," n.d. Two typescript drafts (Folder 5)
  - Article on China, incomplete draft, n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "The Board's Informants," n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - Book reviews, n.d. Three typescript texts (Folder 8)
  - "Boy on a Burning Deck," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "By the Witnesses Against Him," n.d. Three typescript drafts (Folder 10)
  - "Chang Hsin-Hai," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "China, the USSR and the USA in Southeast Asia," n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Chinese Communist Ideology in Evolution," n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Chinese-Russian Relations from Mongol Times to the Present," n.d. Book length text, possibly an early version of China and Russia: The 'Great Game', 1971. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "The Cream of the Jest," n.d. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Crisis in Asia: Matsu and Quemoy," n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "Decline and Fall of the Manchu Empire," n.d. Typescript outline and notes (Folder 17)
  - "Democracy and the New Order," n.d. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - Eulogy for Paul Frillman, n.d. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Fact Sheet - Asia," n.d. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "The Future of Formosa," n.d. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "The Future of Sinkiang," n.d. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - "The Glorious Succession," n.d. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - History of Manchuria, n.d. Notes, genealogical table, research material (in Chinese and Russian), and text. Holograph and typescript (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - "The History of Manchuria," n.d. Notes, outline, and text. Holograph and typescript (Folder 2)
  - "The Homecoming," n.d. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Maneuvers - Naval and Other," n.d. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "John P. Davies and the U.S. Foreign Service," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Let's Cry Treason," n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "The Mad Hatter's Tea Party," n.d. Typescript notes (Folder 7)
  - "Memorandum on the Solution of the Chinese Problem" (authorship uncertain), n.d. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "The Middle East and U.S. Policy," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Neutralism and Communism," n.d. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "Neutralism and Ostrichism," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Notes on revolution and bureaucracy, n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Post Hoc Ergo Propter Hoc," n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "The Significance of Korea," n.d. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Sino-American Relations," book length text, n.d. Typescript draft (Folder 15)
  - "The United States and Asia," n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "The Unsolved China Problem," n.d. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Whose 'Agrarian Reformers'?" n.d. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Winter of the Nationalists' Discontent," n.d. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "The Reform Movement of 1898," 1940 June. Typescript (Box 11., Folder 1)
  - "Assigned to Harbin...," The American Foreign Service Journal, 1948 June. Printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "American Policy in Respect to China," The American Foreign Service Journal, 1948 November. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Communism in China," speech, Colgate University, 1950 July 10. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "No Peking Picnic," The American Foreign Service Journal, 1950 October. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Chinese Frontiers," article submitted to Far Eastern Survey (not published), 1951 April 19. Correspondence and three typescript drafts (attributed to "J. E. N.") (Folder 6)
  - "Chinese Communist Strategy in Foreign Relations," The Annals of the American Academy of Political Science, 1951 September. Correspondence and two typescript drafts (Folder 7)
  - Review of C. Patrick Fitzgerald, Revolution in China, 1952(?). Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "Communist Strategy in Asia," Eastern World, 1952 October. Correspondence and two typescript drafts (Folder 9)
  - "The Significance of Korea," unpublished article, 1952 October 31. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 10)
  - "'Titoism' and the Chinese Communist Regime," The World Today, 1952 December (attributed to "O. E. C."). Correspondence and three typescript drafts (Folder 11)
  - Background memoranda submitted to The Economist, 1953. Correspondence and six typescript texts (Folder 12)
  - Memoranda, largely relating to Chinese history and American foreign policy, 1953-1956. Fourteen typescript texts (Folder 13)
  - "'Plus Ça Change...' in China?" Far Eastern Survey, 1953 January 28. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - Review of Liu, Shaw-tong, Out of Red China, article submitted to Pacific Affairs, 1953 July 15. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Korea and Northeast Asia," The World Today, 1953 September. Correspondence, two typescript drafts, and printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "The Perenniel (sic) China Tangle," unpublished article, 1953 September 26. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Rainbow in the China Sky," unpublished article (signed "Epithemus"), 1953 October 12. Two typescript drafts (Folder 18)
  - "Asians and the Korean Question," unpublished article, 1953 October 19 (Folder 19)
  - Book reviews submitted to The Nation, 1954. Correspondence and three typescript texts (Folder 20)
  - "Federal Loyalty and Security Procedures," 1954 January 6. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "The Perennials," 1954 March 17. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - "Asia and the Geneva Conference," Eastern World, 1954 April. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Thoughts on Indochina," 1954 April 27. Typescript notes (Folder 24)
  - "Chinese Communist Development Programs in Manchuria," paper delivered at the Twelfth Conference, Institute of Pacific Relations, Kyoto, Japan, 1954 September-October. Printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Peking and Moscow Eye Japan," article submitted to The New Statesman and Nation (not published), 1954 November. Correspondence, outline, and typescript (Folder 26)
  - "National Security and Our Foreign Service," The Nation, 1954 December 25. Printed copy (Folder 27)
  - Book reviews submitted to The Nation, 1955. Correspondence and four typescript texts (Folder 28)
  - Editorials submitted to The Nation, 1955. Correspondence and seven typescript texts (Folder 29)
  - "America's 'Entangling Alliance' with Formosa," The World Today, 1955 February. Correspondence and two typescript texts (Folder 30)
  - "Disunity in SEATO," The Nation, 1955 March 12. Typescript and printed copy (Box 12., Folder 1)
  - "The Inner Mongolian Autonomous Region," Eastern World, 1955 April. Printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Quemoy or Asia," The Nation, 1955 April 16. Two typescript drafts and printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Four Horns to an Asiatic Dilemma," The Nation, 1955 May 4. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Japan Turns Back to Asia," The Progressive, 1955 June. Correspondence and printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "The Mongolian People's Republic," Eastern World, 1955 September. Correspondence, typescript, and printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Dragon's Teeth in Korea," The Nation, 1955 September 3. Correspondence, typescript, and printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "United States Defense Policy in the West Pacific," World Today, 1955 October. Correspondence, typescript, and printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Rhee's War on Japan," The Nation, 1955 November 5. Correspondence and printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Divided Vietnam: Second Korea?" The Progressive, 1955 December. Correspondence, typescript, and printed copy (Folder 10)
  - Book reviews submitted to The Nation, 1956. Correspondence and thirteen typescript texts, some being versions of the same article (Folder 11)
  - Editorials submitted to The Nation, 1956. Correspondence and four typescript texts (Folder 12)
  - "Two-Way Streets and the One-Track Mind," article submitted to The Nation (not published), 1956 April. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Formosa in World Perspective," paper delivered at the annual meeting of the Far Eastern Association, Philadelphia, 1956 April 3. Correspondence, program, and two typescript texts (Folder 14)
  - Review of Chinese documents project, submitted to Far Eastern Quarterly, 1956 April 13. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Dead Hand Over Asia," The Progressive, 1956 May. Correspondence and three typescript drafts (Folder 16)